Now let's move on to Claw.
First of all, I would like to talk about our self-designed component.
There are many customizations of this component.
For example, single molding, three-dimensional decoration,
or gas eye button, etc.
These can all be called components.
Before we make the component,
we can go to our Connect mall first.
Let's see if there is a component we want.
This is our Connect mall interface.
In addition to searching for the website connectclawset.com,
we click on the N icon in Claw.
Click on Login.
Here you can see our clothing materials.
Trim here.
We can click on it.
There are also a lot of materials.
We can also make a link login here.
Now let's go to Connect.
Then we can take a look at our shop.
There is a copy here.
Here we have a collaboration with SAB YKK.
They will put their...
The copy is uploaded to the Connect mall to download.
The one with the watermark is the copy that we officially uploaded.
Some copies can be made with panels.
There are some more complex copies that cannot be made with panels.
Next, I will show you...
I will show you how to make copies with panels in Claw.
Now, let's open the document folder of this customized clothing material with me.
You can click on the plus sign in the library.
Add our material document folder to this folder.
After you add it in,
we can take a look at it.
Today, I will show you how to make a copy like this with panels.
First of all,
we use the shape panel tool in the 2D window.
We directly left-click and create this shape panel.
We use it.
This default 500 by 500 millimeters.
Just a 500-millimeter long panel.
Okay.
Next,
we come to the window of this picture shop.
Right-click.
Right-click this picture.
Increase as a sticker.
We will use this picture as a reference picture.
Then use the method of adding a sticker to import it in.
After we import it in,
we can see this picture in the physical window.
In order to make it more delicate,
we can hook its outline.
We can adjust the opacity of this sticker.
Click on this sticker.
Adjust its opacity in the mouse.
Adjust it to about 40 or 50.
Okay.
Next,
we can use this internal shape tool to create this copy of this shape.
We can observe that this copy can be made up of seven small panels.
However,
there are two panels,
the mouth-shaped panel and the T-shaped panel.
These two panels can be repeated.
So,
we only need to draw these three different panels.
Now,
let's draw according to its outline.
First,
draw this mouth-shaped one.
Then,
let's draw this curved panel.
This curved panel.
Next,
let's make this T-shaped one.
We can use the internal multi- demand shape tool to make this.
During the sketching process,
let's click the Shift key
to mark the covering.
This will guarantee that
all the internal lines we have made are horizontal and vertical.
Okay.
After the sketching is complete,
We can now hook it up to the board.
Use the adjustment board tool.
Right-click on the internal line of this curve.
Select the column as the board.
Put it next to this.
And then the T-shape.
Right-click on the T-shape board.
Cut it off.
We can keep the internal line in the middle.
We can use it as a reference when we combine.
The mouth shape is the same.
If we use the column board directly,
the internal line inside will not be retained.
So let's select the external line.
Right-click on it.
Select Cut.
Cut it off directly.
OK.
Now we can combine these boards.
Place it in the correct position.
Right-click on the T-shape board.
Cut it off.
And then select the internal line inside the mouth shape board.
Right-click on it.
Turn it into a hole.
We can delete this sticker.
Delete the sticker of this mouth shape board.
And delete this T-shape.
Just delete it.
OK.
Next, we can duplicate these boards.
Duplicate it.
Select this board.
Ctrl-D.
Duplicate it.
And then we need to duplicate this one.
This board below.
We can directly.
Ctrl-C and Ctrl-V.
Duplicate it.
Right-click on it.
Rotate it.
And then align it to this position.
Then Ctrl-D.
Then we can do the same with the T-shape board.
OK.
Next, we will duplicate this.
Right-click on it.
Select this board, Ctrl plus D, and align it with the number.
We don't need this big board anymore, we can delete it directly.
Then select all the boards, right-click in the 3D window, select Rearrange 2D Arrangement Position.
It will follow the position of the 2D window.
The 3D window is also the same arrangement.
Then we can select the material in the 5D window, and then modify it to the color we want.
This sideboard is a golden effect.
We can adjust it to a golden color, click apply and close.
Then we can adjust its type.
We can adjust it to a metal effect.
We also need to make it thick.
And we can look at this reference picture.
The mouth shape and the T-shape are thicker than the middle shape.
So we...
Select all the boards.
And then select the shape board.
In the parameter editor,
Add a thickness of 8 mm.
Then we can see if there is a certain curve on its side.
Then we can go to the edge curve setting here.
To adjust its curve.
Then we can add a slightly thinner one to the middle shape board.
Add a thickness of 5 mm here.
We can also adjust its edge curve.
Then we can move the board back a little bit.
To give it a sense of level.
Now our board is ready.
Then we can convert it to a copy.
Then we can select all the boards in control A.
In the 3D window, right click.
Find convert.
Copy.
We can convert it to a copy by clicking.
You can see that after I convert it,
the board disappears in the 2D window.
In the 3D window,
the little butterfly icon here
appears as our copy.
And in the 3D window,
it has this small water icon and a size adjustment icon.
We can click on it.
We can click on the copy icon here.
To adjust its weight.
We can adjust it a little bit.
I changed it to 2 grams here.
Then the size here.
Since the precision of our drawing is more accurate.
Then I just made the proportion a little bit bigger.
Now it's very big.
It's almost 10 centimeters long.
So now I need to make it a little bit smaller.
A little bit more delicate.
Then I can adjust it to 20 here.
Now it becomes very small.
Now I have completed the adjustment of the size and weight of this copy.
Similarly, here,
like material and color,
we can also adjust it here.
After adjusting these properties,
we can click on the copy here.
The copy in the property editor.
You can click save.
We can save this trim format copy.
Click save.
Now I'm going to open a cloud.
And then this is what I used in advance.
Our default t-shirt.
Added a piece of clothing.
You can use it to see our components.
Find the trim format component I just saved.
We directly right-click to add to the workspace.
Just click and open it.
You can see it has been added.
We can use the glue tool to stick it to our clothing.
Stick it to our clothing.
Okay.
Just now,
I took you to make our components with a board.
And it's very convenient.
Just click in the cloud.
You can use a key to convert it to a component.
We may have some other situations.
Maybe someone will want to ask.
Teacher, my component has a sticker or text.
You only have one material.
It's easier to do.
What if I have a sticker or text?
What should I do?
Now I'm going to take you to use it.
That is, if we have a sticker or text.
How do you do the component with this project file?
Now I'm going to click.
Then open a new project.
In the material for everyone.
You can see that there are two.
A component of a component file.
There is a name.
It's a metal plate.
Let's drag it in.
What about this?
This is a file for you to make in advance.
You can use it to try it.
Like these two metal plates.
It's all made of textiles.
Textiles are added on top.
You can see that there are some differences between the two of them.
Except for the color.
In our house window.
Click on this plant.
You can see the first one.
The first one.
This one.
This brown one.
This brown component.
This board.
We can see that it has textiles.
Textiles, textiles.
And the rough surface.
This purple one.
I'm going to click.
It has textiles.
Textiles, textiles.
But it doesn't have the rough surface.
And the metal one.
Here's a little explanation for you.
If we say our.
This is the component made of this board.
This one.
This is the component.
This is the component made of this board.
它带有纹理发现置换,我们可以直接像刚刚一样右键直接去做一个转换,我先来转换一下,转换完成之后,它现在已经成功转换了,它的纹理图和发现图都是还在的,包括它的一个置换图都还在,没有任何的丢失。
然后我们再来看一下下面的这个,它是与上面的多了表面粗糙度图,现在如果我来去一键转换的话,那可以看到它会有一些小小的问题,那所以说,我先来撤回,所以说那如果我们的附件带有表面粗糙度图或者是金属图的话,那我们就要用以下的方法来做。
现在呢,我来再去点击新项目,打开这个金属牌贴图这个项目文件,分加到工作区。
当我们的这个附件呢,带有贴图或者是这个纹理图带有表面粗糙度图或者是金属图的话,我们要用以下的方法来做。
大家看一下,现在这个附件呢是用贴图来做的。
我先给大家尝试一下,如果我们还用一开始的很简单的方法,在三个窗网中直接右键去做一个转换的话,那么可以看到,它的贴图会丢失。
所以说我们接下来要用一个办法来去保留它所有的这些图片。
我们进入到这个UV编辑模式中,点击进入UV编辑模式。
选择这个贴图,然后点击自动UV填充。
它会自动的将我们的这个贴图呢填充到最大的一个大小。
好的,然后呢再回到模拟模式下。
选择我们的这个版片。
点击文件导出,OBJ选择的。
我们去储存到我们想要的一个路径中。
然后去给它一个V名。
点击保存。
我们进入这个模式。
我们选择所有的版片,选择所有的贴图。
复附键选择多个目标。
选择厚的。
比例呢毫米百分之百。
然后勾选和文理文件一起保存为一个ZIP文件。
点击确认。
现在呢我们是保存出来了一个ZIP文件。
在这里。
好,接下来呢我们再去打开一个新的Cloud。
再打开一个Cloud。
这个是一个新的Cloud。
找到我们刚刚保存的这个ZIP文件。
右键增加到工作区。
对象类型呢选择附件。
比例毫米百分之百。
点击确认。
好。
大家可以看到啊。
我们现在的贴图被保留下来了。
但是呢可以看到啊。
在物体窗口中的附件这里我们看到了我们的这个附件。
在属性编译器这里呢可以看到它的置换图和表面粗糙度图没有了。
我们需要在手动将它加进来。
打开我给大家的这个素材文件夹。
找到金属牌置换图。
将它放到我们的这个置换图这里。
并且能调一下它的粒子间距和置换程度。
然后呢表面粗糙度图。
把它改成贴图。
同样将它添加进来。
去调整一下它的一个数据啊。
勾选一下反向。
那可以看到啊。
我们的这个。
表面粗糙度图被添加进来了。
把它的金属度可以拉的大一点点。
然后包括它的一个。
整体的一个金属感的一个效果。
也出来了。
然后呢我们可以进一步。
去调整它的一个重量和大小。
同样也是点击物体窗口里的附件啊。
然后去输入它的一个重量。
我这边改成了5克。
然后比例。
比例我这边输入一个50。
它变小了。
接下来呢我们再去。
给它保存。
保存。
点击保存。
这个呢是。
如果我们的附件。
我们的版片呢是带有贴图。
或者是。
纹理上是有表面粗糙度图或者是金属图的。
我们就需要用这个方法来。
制作我们的附件。
我刚刚已经导。
导出了trim格式的金属牌。
现在我来刷新一下。
然后将我们的这个金属牌增加到工作区。
可以看到它被添加进来了。
同样我们可以使用胶水工具将它粘贴在我们的服装上。
那可以看到。
我们刚刚添加进来的表面粗糙度图。
这种效果呢。
依然被保留了。
可以直接去使用它。